-
Speaker 1: Right now, Congress is considering a proposal that would integrate the U.S. and Israeli military industrial complexes more than ever before. That integration would forge collaborations between the U.S. and Israel on just about every defense tech issue of the future, from AI to cybersecurity to drones and so many more.
Speaker 1: And this idea was Benjamin Netanyahu himself. Our factories can become their factories. Our data could become their data. That's pretty scary. The biggest proponents of this proposal are, unsurprisingly, supporters of Israel. Organizations like AIPAC and other groups in the Israel lobby, and of course the members of Congress who help to fund their campaigns.
Speaker 1: It's critical that the American public know that this idea was Benjamin Netanyahu's himself. And you don't have to take my word for it. Benjamin Netanyahu wrote a letter to a member of Congress where he describes this as, quote, "My plan."
Speaker 1: So that's literally a foreign leader telling the U.S. public how it's going to draft its laws. That
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): should not be okay. And so I think this is a very noble position that the Prime Minister has taken to replace the aid with trade agreements, to replace the aid with defense agreements. The risks to this are extraordinary.
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): It effectively ties our
Speaker 1: hands. Any future president that would want to unwind the relationship with Israel would have to undo co-production agreements, licensing agreements, factories we're working on together with Israel, undo intelligence sharing efforts. All of that could take years and cost billions and billions of dollars.
Speaker 3: This is all coming at a time when the American public is sending a clear message to Congress.
Speaker 3: "We want less involvement with Israel, not more." The American public right now are screaming
Speaker 1: out loud they're not okay with the conflict in Gaza, they're not okay with Israel's action in Lebanon, and they're certainly not okay with Israel dragging the U.S. into a war with Iran. I think Americans should be pissed off about this. You know, if you're an American citizen, you expect your government to have a foreign policy that promotes American interests, not the interests of a foreign country.
Speaker 3: Whether that country is Israel or not, you want a foreign policy that's good for you.